Welcome to the witching hour.
The Craft is a horror, drama, fantasy film directed by Andrew Fleming.
A Catholic school newcomer falls in with a clique of teen witches who wield their powers against
all who dare to cross them -- be they teachers, rivals or meddlesome parents.
Sarah, played by Robin Tunney.
Nancy, played by Fairuza Balk.
Bonnie, played by Neve Campbell.
Rochelle, played by Rachel True.
Chris, played by Skeet Ulrich.
Laura Lizzie, played by Christine Taylor.
The Craft is a 1996 American teen supernatural horror film directed by Andrew Fleming
from a screenplay by Peter Filardi and Fleming and a story by Filardi.
The film stars Robin Tunney, Fairuza Balk, Neve Campbell, and Rachel True as four outcast teenage girls at a Los Angeles
parochial high school who pursue witchcraft for their own gain and experience negative repercussions.
The Craft was theatrically released in the United States on
May 3, 1996, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
It received mixed reviews from critics but was a surprise hit nonetheless, earning $6.7 million in
its opening weekend and $55.6 million worldwide, against a budget of $15 million.
The Craft was nominated for the Saturn Awards for Best Horror Film and for Best Supporting
Actress (Balk), and won the MTV Movie Award for Best Fight (Balk and Tunney).
In the years since its release, the film has gained a cult following.
A sequel, The Craft: Legacy, was released on October 28, 2020.
The film explores themes of witch, puberty, magic, suicide attempt, black magic.
The tone is dark and emotional.